Never let the truth ruin a good story.
Street Smart is a thriller, crime, drama film directed by Jerry Schatzberg.
A New York journalist lies when his fake story about a
pimp describes a real pimp up for murder.
Jonathan Fisher, played by Christopher Reeve.
Punchy, played by Kathy Baker.
Alison Parker, played by Mimi Rogers.
Leonard Pike, played by Jay Patterson.
Ted Avery, played by Andre Gregory.
Leo "Fast Black" Smalls, Jr., played by Morgan Freeman.
Street Smart is a 1987 American crime thriller film directed by Jerry Schatzberg and
starring Christopher Reeve, Morgan Freeman, Kathy Baker and Mimi Rogers.
Reeve portrays an ambitious reporter who fabricates an interview with a pimp.
When a real pimp who closely matches the fictional description (Freeman) is indicted for
murder, both he and the prosecutor try to exploit the reporter for their own ends.
The film was released to theatres by Cannon Films on March 20 1987.
Despite being well-received by audiences and critics,
the film was a commercial failure.
The performances of Freeman and Baker were highly praised, and
Freeman considered his role as his film breakthrough.
He was nominated for both an Academy Award and a Golden Globe Award, and won the
Independent Spirit Award for Best Supporting Male for his performance.
The film explores themes of new york city,
journalist, prostitute, court case, pimp.
The tone is emotional and intense.